Hampton L. Carson Papers 1921-1993 Mss.Ms.Coll.83
American Philosophical Society
Hampton L. Carson Papers
1921-1993
Mss.Ms.Coll.83
American Philosophical Society
32.0 Linear feet
The population geneticist Hampton L. Carson spent the major part of his career at Washington University (1949-1963) and the University of Hawaii (1963-1985) investigating the cytogenetics and evolution of Drosophila. As one of the major figures in the Hawaii Drosophila project, he made particularly important contributions to the study of speciation and selective and non-selective evolutionary mechanisms. The Carson Papers (1921-1993) contain correspondence, subject files, manuscripts of published and unpublished works by Carson, papers by colleagues and students, research notes, course material, and photographs, which document Carson's career in genetics. The collection is organized into seven series: I. Correspondence, 1944-1993; II. Subject Files, 1946-1989; III. Works by Carson, 1951-1985; IV. Works by Others, 1949-1987; V. Research Notes, 1921-1993; VI. Course Material, 1943-1986; VII. Photographs, 1948-1985.
Carson,, Hampton L. (Hampton Lawrence), 1914-
Box 1-65
General note
Dobzhansky, Nomination of Hampton Carson to the National Academy of Sciences. Ser. II. National Academy of Sciences.
New York Times, July 5, 1978; see Series II, Clippings
Genetics Note
This collection contains materials which relate to the history of genetics.
Dobzhansky, Theodosius Correspondence (15 items) 1955-1975
Evolution Correspondence (2 folders) 1971-1986
Evolutionary Processes and Theory Workshop Correspondence (2 folders) 1984-1985
Evolutionary Theory Correspondence (2 items) 1983
Genetic Microdifferentiation in Human and Other Animal Populations International Symposium Correspondence (2 folders) 1983-1986
Genetics Records (26 items) 1974-1983
Genetics Society of America Records (2 folders) 1976-1983
International Congress of Genetics Records (2 folders) 1973-1983
Mayr, Ernst Correspondence (7 items) 1978-1986
National Drosophila Research Conference Records (2 folders) 1978-1984
Provine, William B. Correspondence (2 items) 1983
Society for the Study of Evolution Records (2 folders) 1946-1978
Stalker, Harrison Dailey Correspondence (5 items) 1967, 1978
Templeton, Alan Robert Correspondence (60 items) 1970-1984
University of Hawaii Records (7 folders) 1970-1985
Wallace, Bruce Correspondence (3 items) 1973-1983
Wheeler, Marshall R. Correspondence (2 folders) 1952-1992
Related Archival Materials note
Luther Val Giddings, Kenneth Y. Kaneshiro, and Wyatt W. Anderson, Genetics, Speciation, and the Founder Principle (New York: Oxford, 1989). Call no.: 575.1 G36g.
General note
During processing, the collection was re-foldered and re-housed in acid-free folders and boxes. Metal fasteners were removed and replaced with plastic clips when necessary. A separate listing of torn or severely deteriorated manuscripts and manuscripts that need to have glue and tape removed has been compiled by series and submitted to the Conservation Department.
All newspaper clippings were photocopied onto acid-free paper; the original clippings were then discarded. Other brittle or torn items were also photocopied, and when considered valuable, were retained. Photographs have been interleaved with non-buffered, acid-free paper.
Accruals note
Several recent accessions have not yet been calendared and are not reflected in this finding aid.
Immediate Source of Acquisition note
The Carson Papers were donated to the APS Library by Hampton Lawrence Carson in 1994 (accn. no. 1994-631ms.) and subsequently.
Scope and Contents note
The Hampton Lawrence Carson Papers (1921-1993) contain correspondence, subject files, manuscripts of published and unpublished works by Carson, papers by colleagues and students, research notes by Carson, course material, and photographs, which document Carson's career as an evolutionary geneticist.
Oversized materials follow the same series arrangement as noted above. Cross referencing to oversized material appears on the folders in the standard-sized boxes. All photographs and negatives have been removed from Series I-VI and placed in Series VII. Cross references appear in the original series. Reprints have been moved to the printed materials collection of the APS library. If a reprint was found as an enclosure, a photocopy of the title page was filed in its place. To retrieve reprints, consult the card catalog for printed materials.
The papers (31 boxes; 15 linear feet) are divided into seven series:
Series I. Correspondence 1944-1993 3.75 lin. feet
Series II. Subject files 1946-1989 1 lin. foot
Series III. Works by Carson 1951-1985 2.75 lin. feet
Series IV. Works by others 1949-1987 1 lin. foot
Series V. Research notes 1921-1993 3.5 lin. feet
Series VI. Course material 1943-1986 2.5 lin. feet
Series VII. Photographs 1948-1985 0.5 lin. feet
Biographical/Historical note
A population geneticist best known for his work on Drosophila, Hampton Lawrence Carson was born into a distinguished Philadelphia scientific family on November 5, 1914. Carson studied zoology at the University of Pennsylvania, where his great-grandfather, Joseph Carson had been a professor of botany, receiving his AB under Robert Miller Stabler in 1936, and his PhD in 1943. His dissertation on the cytogenetics of darkwinged fungus gnats, "An Analysis of Natural Chromosome Variability in Sciara impatiens" was well received and was published a year later in the Journal of Morphology. According to Theodosius Dobzhansky, this work provided "definitive cytological proof of the chromosomal situations produced by crossing over in inversion heterozygotes." 1
Joining the faculty of Washington University in 1943, Carson rose from assistant professor in 1949 to professor in 1956. In 1951, he was appointed visiting professor of biology at the University of Sao Paulo, Brazil and was a Fulbright Research Scholar in zoology at the University of Melbourne, Australia. Carson began his association with the University of Hawaii in the summers of 1963 to 1967 as a visiting professor and participant in the Hawaiian Drosophila Project, a cooperative venture between tge Universities of Texas and Hawaii which had been initiated by Elmo Hardy and Wilson Stone in 1963 to study Hawaii's 600 unique drosophilid species. In 1970 Carson was appointed Manoa Genetics Professor in the Department of Entomology at Hawaii, where he continued until his retirement in 1985.
Shortly after completing his dissertation, Carson struck up a fruitful collaboration with Harrison Stalker on Drosophila robusta (see Ms. Coll. 23), and from that point on, devoted much of his scientific attention to Drosophila and to elucidating fundamental questions of selection, reproductive isolation, and speciation. Through a careful series of comparative genetic analyses of populations in New Guinea, Australia, the West Indies, Brazil, and many parts of North America, he developed the concepts of heteroselection and homoselection, but his best known research came through the Hawaiian Drosophila Project. After studying the population genetics of eight species endemic to the Hawaiian islands, Carson proposed that speciation in the island chain was tied to the formation of new islands, with new species being slightly different than those in the nearest island, and progressively more different than those in more distant islands. 2 Carson also contributed to the empirical study of effects and quantum selection.
A prolific writer, Carson published over 250 papers between 1934 and 1989 in journals such as Evolution, Genetics, and American Naturalist. He was active in professional societies, serving terms as president of the Society for the Study of Evolution (1971) and the American Society of Naturalists (1973). In 1979 he was elected a member of the National Academy of Sciences, and in 1985 he won the Leidy Medal for his work with the Hawaiian Drosophila Project. The International Symposium on Genetics, Speciation and the Founder Principle was held in his honor in June 1985, resulting in a festschrift, Genetics, Speciation and the Founder Principle (Oxford Press, 1994).
Although Carson retired from the University of Hawaii faculty in 1985, he remained active in research by working off a grant from the National Science Foundation. Currently he lives in Hawaii with his wife Meredith, who worked with him on several field expeditions.
Dobzhansky, Theodosius Grigorievich, 1900-1975; Futuyma, Douglas J., 1942-; Giddings, Luther Val; Gressitt, J. Linsley; Heed, William B.; Heftel, Cecil, 1924-; Manning, Raymond, 1934-; Mayr, Ernst, 1904-2005; Nevo, Evitar; Okada, Toyohi; Pipkin, Sarah B., 1913; Powell, Jeffrey R.; Provine, William B.; Stalker, Harrison D. (Harrison Dailey), 1915-1982; Stone, Wilson Stuart, 1907-1968; Templeton, Alan Robert; University of Hawaii. Department of Genetics; Val, Francisca Carolina do; Wasserman, Marvin, 1929-; Wheeler, Marshall; White, M. J. D., 1943-; Whiting, Phineas W. (Phineas Westcott), 1887-; Yoon, Jong Sik; Drosophila--Genetics; Evolution (Biology); Founder effect; Genetics; Lecture notes; Natural selection; Photographs; Population biology; Speciation (Biology)
- Series I. Correspondence, 1944-1993; 3.75 lin. feet
  Scope and Contents note
  Incoming and outgoing manuscripts and typescript letters, carbons, telegrams, and postcards generated and collected during Carson's career. The bulk of this series covers the 1970s to the 1980s. Correspondents include professional colleagues, students, politicians, and publishers. Files for Alan R. Templeton, a population geneticist who was Carson's student, and Marshall Wheeler, a colleague on the Hawaiian Drosophila Project, contain a significant amount of professional correspondence. Med-fly eradication in Hawaii is the subject of most of the correspondence with members of Congress. Much of the correspondence filed under institutional titles concerns either the organization of a symposium or Carson's administrative or committee responsibilities. Correspondents in Series I include:
  Series I is arranged alphabetically by correspondent's name and then chronologically within each folder.
  Unidentified correspondence has been filed as "Unidentified" and is arranged chronologically. Enclosed manuscripts have been removed from this series and placed in Series III or IV as appropriate. As with the reprints, a photocopy of the title page was filed with the original letter. Cross references are also given for enclosed photographs, which have been removed to Series VII. Letters of reference are filed under the name of the person who is the subject of the letter.
  - Abensohn, Meryl, 1971
  - Academic Press Inc. (London) Limited, 1978
  - The Academy of Natural Sciences, 1984-1985
    -See also Ser.II, same title
  - Academia Nazionale Dei Lincie, 1980-1981
  - The Academy of Natural Sciences, 1984-1985
  - Ahearn, Jayne N., 1981
  - Akaka, Daniel K., 1978-1985
  - Aki, James, 1981
  - Alee, Ralph H., 1956
  - Allard, R. W., 1978
  - Allen, Garland E., 1992
  - Ambrosino, Gabriele, 1978
  - American Academy of Arts and Sciences. Conference on the Synthesis in Evolutionary Biology, 1973-1980
    -See also Ser.I, Harvard University Press
    -See also Ser.III, "Embryology and the 'Modern Synthesis' in Evolutionary Biology"
  - The American Naturalist, 1964-1987
    Kaneshiro, Kenneth Y.
    - See also Ser.II, same title
  - American Philosophical Society, 1982-1983
  - American Society of Naturalists, 1971-1978
  - Anderson, Wyatt W., 1978-1988
  - Andrews, Henry, 1978
  - Angel, Edwardo, 1969
  - Annales de la Societe Entomologique de France, 1987
  - Annest, Joseph Lee, 1973-1978
  - Annual Review of Ecology and Systematics, 1973-1984
  - Aoki, Betty, 1978
  - Archie, James W., 1983-1984
    Simon, Christine M.
  - Arcos-Teran, Laura, 1976
  - Arita, Lorna H., 1982-1984
  - Ariyoshi, George R., 1978-1980
  - Arnaud, Paul H., 1984
  - Ashburner, Michael, 1970
  - Ashton, Geoffrey C., 1978
    -See also Ser.I, University of Hawaii
  - Association of Systematic Collections, 1981-1984
  - Atkins, Gus, n.d.
    -See United States.Department of Transportation. Federal Aviation Administration.
  - Atchley, William R., 1978-1981
    -See also Ser.I, Woodruff, David S.
  - Australian Academy of Science, 1984-1985
    -See also Ser.II, Australian Academy of Science--Symposium on Rates of Evolution.
    -See also Ser.III, "Population Genetics, Evolutionary Rates and NeoDarwinism"
  - Australian National University. Research School of Biological Sciences., 1985
  - Australian Research Grants Committee, 1978
  - Avise, John C., 1975-1983
  - Ayala, Francisco, 1973-1978
  - Baimai, Visut, 1972-1982
  - Bajana, Jose D., 1976-1977
    Some in Spanish
  - Band, Henrietta T., 1982-1989
  - Barker, J.S.F., 1984-1985
  - Barr, H.J., 1972
  - Basden, E.B., 1952
  - Behavior Genetics, 1975-1976
  - Bernice Pauahi Bishop Estate, 1979
  - Bernice Pauahi Bishop Museum, 1974-1980
    United States. Department Of Agriculture
  - Berry, R.J., 1971
    Ashton, Geoffrey C.
  - Beverley, Stephen M., 1985
  - Bishop, John Guy, 1982-1984
  - Blackman, Roger L., 1979
  - Bliss, Dorothy, 1964-1969
  - Blum, Stanley Delbert Jr., 1982
  - Bock, Ian R., 1975-1984
  - Bodnaryk, Robert P., 1970
  - Borecki, Ingrid, 1979
  - Boyer, William H., 1980
  - Brace, C. Loring, 1982
  - Bremner, Donald A., 1979
  - Brenner, Theodore, 1970
  - Brewbaker, James L., 1978-1981
  - Brezinsky, Laura, 1984
  - The British Broadcasting Corporation, 1972-1981
    -See also Ser.II, British Broadcasting Corporation. "The Life Game"
  - The British Broadcasting Corporation. The Open University, 1978-1980
  - Brito da Cunha, A., 1963
  - Brnic, Danko, 1964-1970
  - Brokaw, Barbara, 1975
  - Brussard, Peter F., 1983
  - Bryant, Peter J., 1979-1980
  - Burns, John, 1973
  - Bush, Guy L., 1982-1984
  - Buzzati-Traverso, Adriano, 1951
    Some in German
  - Calahan, James T., n.d.
    -See Ser.I, National Science Foundation
  - Cambridge University Press, 1979
  - Canadian Journal of Zoology, 1984-1989
  - Canal Zone Biological Area, n.d.
    -See Monyihan, M.
  - Carson, Meredith S., n.d.
    -See Ser.I, Ikeda, Horishi
  - Carter, Christine Lee, 1979
  - Carter, J. Cedric, 1949
  - Catcheside, David G., 1978
  - Cattell, Raymond B., 1980-1981
  - Chamberlain, Joseph M., 1964
  - Chance, Britton, 1978
  - Chang, Linda, 1981-1984
  - Chitwood, May Belle H., 1965
  - Charles Darwin Research Station, 1976-1978, n.d.
    Suarez, Teodoro
  - Choi, Young, 1973
  - Christian, Joe C., 1973
  - Clay, Jane Scarola, 1973
  - Clegg, Michael T., 1981-1983
  - Colonization, Succession and Stability Symposium, 1983-1986
  - Columbia University Press, 1961-1978
    -See also Ser.II, Heredity and Human Life
  - Conant, Patrick, 1981
  - Conant, Shelia, 1978-1981
  - Connors, George J., n.d.
    -See Ser.I, Sunset House
  - Conference on Macroevolution, 1980
  - Corbett, Bob, 1966
    -See also Ser.I, Saint Louis University
  - Coyne, Jerry, n.d.
    -See Ser.I, Evolution
  - Crane, Jocelyn, 1964
  - Craddock, Elysse Margaret, n.d.
    -See Ser.I, Craddock-Kambysellis, Elysse Margaret
  - Craddock-Kambysellis, Elysse Margaret, 1972-1982
  - Creutz, E., 1978
    -See also Ser.I, Bernice Pauahi Bishop Museum
  - Crews, David, 1982-1986
  - Crow, James F., 1982-1983
  - Dacanay, Jann Hisae (Takenada), 1990
  - Danks, David, 1982
  - David, Jean R., 1980-1985
  - Day, Max F., 1983-1985
  - S.S. Daydream, 1967
  - Delfinado, Mercedes, 1967
  - Dell, R.K., 1967
  - Devaney, Dennis M., 1966
  - Dever, Daniel dJ., 1980-1981
  - Dickinson, W. J., 1980-1982
  - Dobzhansky, Theodosius, 1955, 1971-1975; 15.0 Item(s)
    Phaff, Herman
    Biographical and personal data; Drosophila genetics; Publication; Scientific organizations, meetings, programs; Teaching; Travel -- Invitations, arrangements
  - Doer, Carolyn, 1965-1967
  - Dover, Gabriel, 1983
  - DoVal, Francisca Carolina, 1980-1982
  - Drosophila Information Service, 1985
  - Dwyer, John D., 1954
  - Ecology, 1955
  - Edelston, Fred, 1964
  - Egyptian Journal of Genetics and Cytology, 1971-1972
  - Ehrman, Lee, 1973-1986
  - Encyclopaedia Britannica, 1970-1973
  - Enders, Robert K., 1958
  - Entomologia Generalis, 1981-1982
  - Entomological Society of America, 1967-1984
  - Equinox, 1983-1986
  - Erbe, Richard W., 1981
  - Etges, William J., 1983-1984
  - Ethical Society of Saint Louis, 1951-1963
  - Evolution, 1971-1986; 2 folders
    Coyne, Jerry
    Society for the Study of
    Evolution
    Business; Drosophila genetics; Editorial matters; Molecular genetics; Population genetics; Publication -- Evolution; Referee's report; Reviews; Society for the Study of Evolution; Spiess, Eliot B.; Unpublished manuscripts, notes, etc.
  - Evolution Today, 1980
  - Evolutionary Processes and Theory -- Workshop, 1984-1985; 2 folders
    Behavioral genetics, IQ; Conferences and symposia; Evolution; Invitations; Lectures, public speaking; Molecular genetics; Population genetics; Publication; Travel -- Israel; Unpublished manuscripts, notes, etc.
  - Evolutionary Theory, 1983; 2.0 Item(s)
    Publication -- Evolutionary Theory; Referee's report
  - Experientia, 1977-1981
  - Fairchild, Alexander G.B., 1958
  - Fenton, C. Stephen, 1981
  - Fernandez, Bernal, 1959
  - Fogg, George S., 1964
  - Fontdevila, Antonio, 1978
  - Ford, E.B., 1974
  - Frank, M. Bart, 1982
  - Freed, Leonard A., 1986
    Whitehall Foundation
  - Freeling, Michael, 1980
  - Freire-Maia, dertia, 1973
  - Fuerst, Paul A., 1974
  - Futuyma, Douglas J., 1984
  - Gagne, Wayne C., 1978, 1987
    Bernice Pauahi Bishop Museum
  - Gall, Joseph, 1978
  - Galore, M., 1977
  - Gardner, R. Allen, 1979
  - Gates, David M., 1974
  - Gebruder, Borntraeger Verlagsbuchhandlung, 1970-1973, 1981
  - Genetic Microdifferentiation in Human and Other Animal Populations International Symposium, 1983-1986; 2 folders
    -See also Ser.VII (oversized), same title
    -See also Ser.VII, Ahuja, Yog
    Conferences and symposia; Drosophila genetics; Human genetics; International Congress of Genetics -- Fifteenth Congress; Neel, James V.; Population genetics; Publication; Travel -- India; Unpublished manuscripts, notes, etc.
  - The Genetics Society of Israel, 1978
    International Genetics Society
  - Genetics, 1974-1983; 26.0 Item(s)
    Business; Cytogenetics; Drosophila genetics; Editorial matters; Genetics Society of America; Lewontin, Richard Charles; Publication -- Evolution; Publication -- Genetics; Referee's report; Unpublished manuscripts, notes, etc.
  - Genetics Society of America, 1976-1983; 2 folders
    American Society of Human Genetics; Behavioral genetics, IQ; Business; Committee activities; Genetics Society of America; Human genetics; Human genetics -- Race; International Congress of Genetics -- Fourteenth Congress; National Science Foundation; Population genetics; Publication -- Genetics; Russian politics and science; Scientific organizations, meetings, programs; Travel -- Invitations, arrangements
  - Geo Journal, 1983
  - Ghiselin, Michael, 1981
  - Gibbs, A.J., 1979
  - Giddings, Luther Val, 1980-1984
  - Gifford, Charles, 1964-1965
  - Gilligan, George N., 1963
  - Glick, Thomas F., 1992-1993
  - Go, Rodney C.P., 1975
  - Golubovsuy, M.D., 1977
  - Goldschmidt, Elizabeth, 1962-1964
  - Gomez, A., 1963
  - Gomez P., Luis D., 1976
  - Goodman, Madeleine J., 1981-1984
  - Goodman, Morris, 1976
  - Gordon, Cecil C., 1950
  - Gould, Leonard, 1965
  - Gralnick, Beverly, 1972
  - Grant, Ulysses J., 1960
    The Rockefeller Foundation
  - Greater Saint Louis Citizens' Committee for Nuclear Information, 1958
  - Green, C.A., 1983
  - Green, Chris, n.d.
    -See Ser.I, Paterson, Hugh
  - Gregg, Thomas, 1977
  - Gressitt, J. Linsley, 1975-1980
    -See also Ser.I, International Journal of Entomology
  - Grimaldi, David A., n.d.
    -See Ser.I, Okada, Toyohi, Folder #2
  - Grossfield, Joseph, 1972
  - Grossman, Abraham, 1974
  - Guardia, Tomas, 1960
  - Hagino, Gerald, 1984
  - Hagiwara, Carol, 1971
  - Halka, O., 1970
  - Hardy, D. Elmo, 1969-1972
  - Harper, John L., 1989
    National Academy of Sciences
  - Harvard University Press, 1980
  - The Hastings Center, 1981
  - Hathaway, William, 1960
  - Hawaii. Department of Agriculture, 1967-1970
  - Hawaii. Department of Land and Natural Resources, 1979-1985
  - Hawaii Audubon Society, 1978-1987
  - Hawaiian Entomological Society, 1979-1984
    University of Hawaii
  - Heatwole, Harold and Audrey, 1962-1965
    Niederkorn, Jack
  - Hedrick, Philip W., 1978
  - Heed, William B., 1953-1970
    Wheeler, Marshal R.
  - Heftel, Cecil, 1977-1985
  - Henslee, Earl D., 1972
  - Heredity, 1980-1981
  - Hiatt, Robert W., 1966
  - Hill, Richard W., 1982-1983
  - Hiraizumi, Yuichiro, 1982-1983
  - Hiraoka, Lea R., 1983
  - Hogue, Charles L., 1972
  - Holt, Milton, 1983
  - Honda-Yafuso, Masako, 1984
    -See also Oversized
  - The Honolulu Advertiser, 1975-1982
  - The Honolulu Star-Bulletin, 1981-1982
  - Hoover, W. Scot, 1978
  - Hopkins, John W., 1970
  - Howard Hughes Medical Institute. Molecular Biology and Evolutionary Theory Workshop, 1983-1984
  - Hsu, T.C., 1951-1952
  - Howes, W., 1964
  - Huettel, Milton D., 1983
  - The Humanist, 1976
  - Hunt, John A., 1977
  - Hunter, Francis and Alice, 1960-1962
  - Idrobo, Jesus M., 1960
  - Ikeda, Hiroshi, 1970-1980
    Carson, Meredith S.
  - Ikeda, Kiyoshi, 1981
  - Ingle, Dwight, 1964
  - Inouye, Daniel K., 1980-1985
  - International Chromosome Conference, 1980
  - International Commission on Zoological Nomenclature, 1973-1974
  - International Congress of Entomology, 1972-1980
  - International Congress of Genetics, 1973-1983; 2 folders
    Conferences and symposia; Crow, James F.; Drosophila genetics; Evolution; International Congress of Genetics -- Fifteenth Congress; International Congress of Genetics -- Fourteenth Congress; International Congress of Genetics -- Thirteenth Congress; Invitations; Medvedev, Zhores A.; Population genetics; Publication; Russian politics and science; Travel -- Invitations, arrangements; Unpublished manuscripts, notes, etc.
  - International Congress of Systematic and Evolutionary Biology, 1972-1984
  - International Genetics Society, n.d.
    -See Ser.I, Genetics Society of Israel
  - International Journal of Entomology, 1973-1983
    -See also Ser.I, Gressitt, J. Linsey
  - Jacobi, James, 1978
  - Jacobs, Patricia A., 1972
  - Jaenike, John, 1984-1986
  - Jallon, Jean-Marc, 1985
  - Jeffery, Duane E., 1973-1978
  - Johnson, George, 1975
  - Johnson, Ron, 1978
  - Johnson, Walter Erwin, 1972-1975
  - Johnston, Spencer, 1971
  - Jones, S., 1967-1968
  - Kambysellis, Michael P., 1971-1990
    -See also Ser.I, Prakash, Satya
  - Kamen, Martin D., 1978
  - Kanapi, Carmen, 1967-1968
  - Kaneshiro, Kenneth Y, 1977-1984
    Bajana, Jose D..
  - Kaufman, Thomas C., 1977
  - Kelly, Susan Jean, 1978
  - Ketron, Inc., 1979
  - Kichuk, Maryanne R., 1980
  - Kidd, Kenneth K., 1973
  - Kidwell, Margaret G., 1979-1982
  - Kimura, Arthur, 1980-1981
  - Kimura, M.T., 1976
  - King, Jack Lester, 1976
  - King, Jean, 1978
  - King, Max, 1985
  - King, Robert C., 1982-1983
  - Kinsley, Richard N. Jr., 1964
  - Kirby, G.C., 1971-1972
  - Kitagawa, Osamu, 1978-1983
  - Kitaji, Gail, 1978
  - Kjargaard, John, 1978
  - Kluge, Arnold G., 1970
  - Koehn, Richard K., 1983
  - Krimbas, Costas B., 1962
  - Lambert, Dave, n.d.
    -See I. Paterson, Hugh
  - Lamoreux, Charles, 1978
    Ziegler, Alan
  - Lande, Russell, 1982-1983
  - Lee, Roberta E., 1981
  - Lenney, Jim, 1978
  - Leon, Jorge, 1956-1959
  - Leung, Lai Fun, 1972
  - Lewin, Alfred S., 1982
  - Lewis, E.B., 1972
  - Lewis, Ralph W., 1980
  - Lightcap, Joy, 1976
  - Lindsley, Dan L., 1978
  - Locke, Robert E., 1985
  - Lutheran High School Central, 1959
    -See also Ser.III, "The Making of a Scientist"
  - Lyttle, Terrence W., 1983-1985